there is a new keyword coming to
JavaScript the keyword is using and is
meant to be used when we initialize a
variables just like we have VAR const
and let we now have using using will be
very useful for managing resources in
your JavaScript programs to make them
run faster if we don't manage resources
correctly our program will take more
memory than it needs making it run
slower or even crashing check out this
example here we have a get users
function where we are getting a
connection to a database we are running
a query and returning the results of the
query it looks fine but it has a problem
can you catch it there is a big problem
we are not closing the connection to the
database if we keep doing this across
our code base we're going to keep
creating new connections without getting
rid of them potentially overloading the
database ideally we should close the
connection to the database when we are
done using it that is better but we
still have a problem if for some reason
the second line of our function throws
an error and the query can't run the
code that is closing the connection to
the database will never run again
leaving the connection open to fix this
we can use a try catch finally block if
we do that no matter what happens on the
try and catch blocks the finally block
will always run closing the connection
to the database the problem with this
approach is that everywhere in our code
where we use the database we will always
have to remember to close it manually
how cool would it be if there was a way
to close the connection to the database
automatically when it stops being used
that is what the using keyword is for
when we create variables with a using
keyword instead of lead or const they
will be disposed once the variable is
out of scope and no longer in use let's
first understand how it works here we
have a function get resource this
function is returning an object that
contains some data and it also contains
a symbol that this post function that
prints by word in our main function we
are creating a my resource variable with
the using keyword and not let or cons we
are then printing the data of the
resource which is hello world and
finally we are calling main because we
are returning an object with a symbol
that displays property and we are using
the using keyword JavaScript will
consider it a resource and automatically
once the main function finishes and the
my resource variable is out of scope
JavaScript will run the code on the
symbol that this pose function that will
print by word as you can see the using
keyword is half of the story it is not
enough to just replace const with using
we also need to write the code that will
run when the variable is disposed off
and that code goes inside of a function
assigned to symbols that this post now
that we know this we can improve our
database code first we have to modify
the getdb function which is the one
giving us access to a resource
internally the getdb function is just
connecting to the database and returning
access to it we're going to change it to
look like this now the get DB function
returns an object the object has a
connection to the database and it has a
symbol that I think this pose function
that is closing the connection to the
database in this case instead of using
symbols that dispose we are using
symbols that a sync dispose because our
dispose code needs to use a sync await
now we can change the get users function
to look like this we are now creating
the DB variable with the using keyword
and because we are using symbol dot as
saying this pose we have to write a
weight before using the B I know it's
kind of weird to have two await on the
same line so remember that the first
await is to await that this postcode and
the second one is to await the code that
connects to our database after those
changes the moment they get user's
function ends JavaScript will
automatically call the symbol that a
sync this pose function we wrote which
is going to close the connection to our
database so now as long as we use the
using keyword whenever we want to get
access to our database we can be sure
that when we are done using that
variable it will always be correctly
disposed off and the connection will be
closed the using keyword is very very
useful not only for database connections
but also for dealing with files that
need to be closed streams of data
websockets connections and more the
using keyword is not part of JavaScript
just yet the proposal for it is on stage
3 of 4. it's almost there if you can't
wait and want to try it out you can use
it on typescript version 5.2 which is
currently available I hope you found
this video useful if you did please like
it share it with your friends and
subscribe to the channel and click the
link below if you want to learn
JavaScript or typescript for absolutely
free also I just finished uploading the
latest version update for the free tutor
clone with Firebase and react course as
well as the CSS flexbox and grid layout
masterclass so check them out by
clicking on the link below
see you on the next one bye
thank you